Michael Takeuchi

Phoenix, AZ 85016 | 310-256-8272 | Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Website

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Web developer with knowledge in Ruby and Javascript, passionate about creating web applications. Understanding in RESTful standards, with experience in prioritizing tasks utilizing test-driven development. Bringing a background in sales, I have strong skills in collaborating and effectively communicating with a team, as well as handling customer needs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Wine Journal - Github | Website

Wine journal to document wine profiles.

- Designed Rails API backend with React frontend and used Material UI to build components and styling.
- Stored data on postgresql to record wine details with associations to varietals and origins.

BoxPlus- Github | Website

Movies app to Lookup details about films and tv shows.

- Constructed a React app with react-router to display homepage, and movie show page with details.
- Utilized The Movie Database, to retrieve movies and tv show data, including actors and actresses.

Social Golf - Github | Website

Add and review golf courses that you and others have played at.

- Developed Javascript web app with CRUD functionality, and used Bootstrap framework for styling.
- Utilized mapbox to display a map and marker for golf courses, and cloudinary to store images.

EXPERIENCE

Southern Glazer's Wine & Spirits

Torrance, CA

Chain Sales Merchandiser

05/2016 - 03/2020

- Built displays in 50% of accounts that helped buyers reduce inventory by 20% and increased sales by over 30% YoY, during Q4 in 2018.
- Helped 5 new accounts organize wine and liquor department plans during grand openings.

Endeavor Society

Santa Monica, CA

Finance Intern

10/2015 - 12/2015

- Created spreadsheets to record projected profits for planned events the organization would host.
- Contributed to designing an employee performance tracker, to provide insight into employees' effectiveness and efficiency at work.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/2020 - 11/2020

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA 06/2015

Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Economics